Maxwell Zhu

Front-End Software Developer

maxwellzhu123@gmail.com https://maxwellzhudev.com (64)223149243

Recent graduate from the University of Auckland with degrees in Computer Science, Psychology, and Bioengineering. With 2.5 years of experience as a Graduate Teaching Assistant, I have taught Python, Java, artificial intelligence, and discrete mathematics. My Master's project involved developing and optimising a spiking neural network in Python to replicate neural circuits, showcasing my skills in software development and advanced computational modelling.

Work Experience

Graduate Teaching Assistant

University of Auckland | Auckland

Jan 2022 - Jul 2024

As a GTA within the Department of Computer Science, I was responsible for running laboratories/tutorials, marking assignment submissions, providing technical consultation under one-on-one circumstances, and invigilating closed-book assessments. Subject areas that were part of my teaching included:

- Data structures and algorithms in Python
- Implementing OOP-designs with Java
- · Discrete structures in mathematics
- Optimisation problems, NLP and probabilistic reasoning
- Computer systems and hardware
- Image processing and computer graphics

Full Stack Developer Intern

MyBig5 | Auckland

Jan 2021 - Jun 2021

During my time at MyBig5, I worked with building APIs using the .NET framework, as well as developed front-end skills in HTML, CSS and Javascript by improving the functionality and appearance of the company website.

Volunteer Experience

President Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

University of Auckland Badminton Club

As club president, I successfully led a 25-member committee in organising and delivering a diverse range of activities, including weekly sports sessions, social events, competitive tournaments, and cultural events. I was responsible for overseeing the club's management and ensuring that we consistently met key productivity and financial milestones.

• UABC secured Sports Club of the Year Award during my tenure for the first time since its inception.

Core Skills

React, Javascript, CSS, HTML, Python, Algorithms and Data Structures, Adaptability, Leadership, Source Control, Linux, Java, OOP, Teamwork, Problem-Solving, Package Management, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Data Analysis, Computational Modelling

Education

University of Auckland

Jan 2023 - Jul 2024

Master of Engineering Bioengineering

University of Auckland Jan 2022 - Dec 2022

Bachelor of Science (Honours) Computer Science GPA 6.1 / 9

University of Auckland Jan 2019 - Dec 2021

Bachelor of Science Computer Science and Psychology GPA 8.3 / 9

Languages

English (Native), Mandarin Chinese (Conversational)

Awards

University of Auckland Bioengineering Master's Scholarship

Jul 2024

Jan 2022

Auckland Bioengineering Institute

Fully-covered cost-of-living stipend and research course fees.

University of Auckland Postgraduate Scholarship

University of Auckland

Fully-covered cost-of-living stipend and research course fees.